(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T04:13:42.583486",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
what an amazing night
やたら very nice
it's super very nice.
ok follow me , listen to my fluffy flow
O.K., follow me, listen to my fluffy flow!
わ た わたし ちがい らない 月 が 昇っ て
Watashi... differences don't matter as the moon rises,
光る ネオンライト ねえ ごらん 夜 が 始まる
glowing neon lights, look, the night begins.
めえめえ 泣いていたって 月は戻んない
Bleating and crying won't bring back the moon.
ただ 落ち込み 枕にダイブ なんてナンセンス
Feeling down and diving into your pillow is nonsense.
夢 だけで見る なんてもったいないよね？ (oh yeah!)
Isn't it a waste to only see it in your dreams? (Oh yeah!)
お利口さんたち が 眠っている 間に生まれる marvelous!
While the good kids are asleep, something marvelous is born!
君も目撃者に なりたいでしょ？ 沈黙は "yes" と同義
You want to be a witness too, right? Silence equals "yes."
make you hot 全員ハイテクノロジー 猛って いる このシーン what an amazing
Make you hot, everyone's high-tech, raging in this scene, what an amazing...
さながら 宵 の 摩天楼 ふわふわ fooo wha a !
Like skyscrapers at dusk, fluffy, fooo wha a!
退屈 クラウド な 日常 から 連れ出し て あげ ましょ う ( yeah ! )
Let me take you away from the boring, cloudy everyday life! (Yeah!)
赤ら様 酔い そう な テンション ふわふわ fooo wha a !
An obvious, intoxicating tension, fluffy, fooo wha a!
crowded ( crowded ! ) 歌っ て ( 歌っ テ ! ) 煙 と 角 に 巻い て 堂々 dawn ! ! !
Crowded (crowded!), sing (sing!), wrapped in smoke and corners, proudly dawn!!!
まず 自分 が 楽しめ なけれ ば 共鳴 する なんて あり 得 ない ん だ から
First you've got to enjoy yourself, resonance is impossible otherwise,
喜び の お裾分け for you ステージ の 上 から go for broke
sharing the joy with you, from the stage, go for broke!
yippee yippee yo yippee yeah yippee yo / sheep sheep yo sheep yeah sheep yo
ほら こっち だ よ 華やか な 世界 へ おいで ( oh yeah ! )
Hey, come over here, to this gorgeous world! (Oh yeah!)
お利口さんたち も 眠れ ちまいやしない 巻き込む marvelous !
Even the good kids won't be able to sleep, getting dragged into something marvelous!
予測 不能 の swing magic 身体 が 勝手 に 反応 し 反応 し ちゃう でしょ ？
Unpredictable swing magic, your body reacts on its own, doesn't it?
さあ 一緒 に ダンス what an amazing
Now let's dance together, what an amazing...
さながら 宵 の 摩天楼 ふわふわ fooo wha a !
Like skyscrapers at dusk, fluffy, fooo wha a!
退屈 クラウド な 日常 から 連れ出し て あげ ましょ う ( yeah ! )
Let me take you away from the boring, cloudy everyday life! (Yeah!)
赤ら様 酔い そう な テンション ふわふわ fooo wha a !
An obvious, intoxicating tension, fluffy, fooo wha a!
crowded ( crowded ! ) 歌っ て ( 歌っ て ! ) 煙 と 角 に 巻い て 堂々 dawn ! ! !
Crowded (crowded!), sing (sing!), wrapped in smoke and corners, proudly dawn!!!
堂々 dawn ! ! ! go for broke
Proudly dawn!!! Go for broke!
ギラギラ の スパンコール 着飾る は 見たまんま
Dressed in glittering sequins, just as you see.
ゴージャス かつ フローラル かつ グローバル な 大人 さ
A gorgeous, floral, and global adult.
大胆不敵な デンディズム digi dan dan 観客 も 一流 の フィクサー ばかり
Audacious dandyism, digi dan dan, the audience is full of top-tier fixers.
ギリギリ 悪く ない 社交 場 の よう な 遊び場 で 飛び跳ね ちゃおう over the border
Let's jump around in a playground like a borderline not-bad social club, over the border!
太陽 を 寝不足 に する くらい 騒げ again and again . . .
Party hard enough to make the sun sleep-deprived, again and again...
what an amazing night
やたら very nice
pretty very nice!
ok follow me , listen to my fluffy flow
OK, follow me, listen to my fluffy flow.
わTわしちゃいられない 月が昇って
With no time to waste, the moon rises,
光るネオンライト ねぇ ごらん 夜が始まる
and glowing neon lights—look, the night begins.
めめめ泣いていたって ツキは戻んない
Crying "meow, meow, meow" won't bring back your luck,
ただ落下込み 枕にダイブ なんてナンセンス
just sinking and diving into a pillow is nonsense.
夢だけで見る なんてもったいないよね ？ ( oh yeah ! )
It's a waste to only see it in dreams, right? (Oh yeah!)
お利口さんたちが眠っている間に生まれる marvelous !
Marvelous things are born while the good kids sleep!
君も目撃者になりたいでしょ ？ 沈黙は “ yes ” と同義
You want to be a witness too, right? Silence means "yes".
make you hot 総員ハイテクノロジー
Make you hot, all with high technology.
猛っているこのシーン what an amazing
This fierce scene—what an amazing...
さながら宵の摩天楼 ふわふわ fooo wha a !
Just like a skyscraper at dusk, fluffy fooo wha a!
退屈クラウドな日常から 連れ出してあげましょう ( yeah ! )
Let's take you out from the boring cloudy routine! (Yeah!)
あからさま酔いそうなテンション ふわふわ fooo wha a !
An obviously intoxicating tension, fluffy fooo wha a!
crowded ( crowded ! ) 歌って ( 歌って ! )
Crowded (crowded!), sing (sing!),
煙と角に巻いて 堂々 dawn ! ! !
wrapped in smoke and horns, grandly, dawn!!!
yippee yippee yo yippee yeah yippee yo
sheep sheep yo sheep yeah sheep yo
ほら こっちだよ 華やかな世界へ おいで ( oh yeah ! )
Look, it's this way, come to a gorgeous world! (Oh yeah!)
お利口さんたちも眠れちゃいられない 巻き込む marvelous !
The good kids can't stay asleep, involved in something marvelous!
予測不能の swing magic 身体が勝手に反応し反芻しちゃうでしょ ？
Unpredictable swing magic—your body reacts and ruminates on its own!
さあ 一緒にダンス what an amazing
Come on, let's dance together, what an amazing...
さながら宵の摩天楼 ふわふわ fooo wha a !
Just like a skyscraper at dusk, fluffy fooo wha a!
退屈クラウドな日常から 連れ出してあげましょう ( yeah ! )
Let's take you out from the boring cloudy routine! (Yeah!)
あからさま酔いそうなテンション ふわふわ fooo wha a !
An obviously intoxicating tension, fluffy fooo wha a!
crowded ( crowded ! ) 歌って ( 歌って ! )
Crowded (crowded!), sing (sing!),
煙と角に巻いて 堂々 dawn ! ! !
wrapped in smoke and horns, grandly, dawn!!!
堂々 dawn ! ! !
Grandly, dawn!!!
go for broke
ギラギラのスパンコール
Dressed in glittering sequins,
着飾るは見立てまま
just as you see it.
こんばんは！
Good evening!
どうもどうも！
Hello, hello!
いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome!
ラムベガスへ！
To Lamb Vegas!
ということで、角巻わため4周年でございます！
And so, it's Tsunomaki Watame's 4th anniversary!
みんないつも本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much, as always!
いやコメントもね、いっぱいいっぱいありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the comments too!
おめでと、おめでとう、ありがとうございます！
Congrats, congratulations, thank you!
いやみんなのおかげで本当にここまで楽しく活動できたと思います！
I really feel like I've been able to enjoy my activities up to now thanks to everyone!
そこですみんなにお願いがあるんですけどいいですか？
So, I have a favor to ask everyone, is that okay?
えー、こちら…の、こちら！
Um, this... over here, this!
ハッシュタグが今日ありまして、#角巻わため4周年！
There's a hashtag today, #TsunomakiWatame4thAnniversary!
ぜひいっぱいいっぱいスクショとかね、撮って、たくさんポストとかね！
Please take lots of screenshots and make lots of posts!
していただけたらなと思います！よろしくお願いします！
I'd really appreciate it! Thank you so much!
え、ちょっと見て、これ！
Um, look at this!
ブンブンブン…怒られないかな？
Zoom zoom zoom... won't I get in trouble?
大丈夫かな？あまり暴れますとね、危ないですからね。
Will it be fine? If I swing around too much, it's dangerous.
みんな足元に気をつけてくださいね！
Everyone, please watch your step!
いや見て、これ！ステージ作っていただきました！
Look at this! They made this stage for me!
いやー、作っていただきました！
Oh man, they built it for me!
これはね、わためーリングスウィングのMVですね！
This is the MV for "Watame-ring Swing"!
ミュージックビデオを再現していただいて、すごくないですか？
They recreated the music video, isn't that amazing?
かなりリアルにMVを再現してくれてて、どうですか？
They recreated the MV so realistically, what do you think?
ここで今からいっぱいいっぱい歌って、踊って、楽しい楽しい歌謡をして行きたいと思いますよ！
From here on, I want to sing a lot, dance, and have a super fun song show!
準備はいいですか？
Are you ready?
あそこのステッキもね、見て！
And look at that stick over there!
これ！あのー、わためいとの毛をね、むしって作ってもらいました！
This! They plucked Watamates' hair to make it!
いやみんな毛の提供ありがとう！こんなかっこいいステッキになりました！本当にありがとう、いっぱい使いたいと思います！
Thanks everyone for providing hair! It became such a cool stick! Thank you so much, I want to use it a lot!
これからもね、いやもうみんな待てないよね？MC長いて、思ってんの、大丈夫かな？
From now on... wait, everyone can't wait anymore right? Thinking the MC is long, is that okay?
この後は、たくさんたくさんゲストの方と歌って踊ったりしていきますので！
After this, I'll be singing and dancing with lots and lots of guests!
まだまだ盛り上がっていきましょう！行くぞー！
Let's keep getting hyped up! Let's go!
寂しくて一人の夜は
On lonely nights alone,
秘密の扉を探して
searching for a secret door,
秘密の扉を抜けてきて
slipping through the secret door,
君が oh yeah!
you go oh yeah!
shake it!
分かち合って 爆発させ
Share it, let it explode,
4周年おめでとう！上げてきな！
Happy 4th anniversary! Pump it up!
お・お・お・お・お求め 限界を！
Seek out your limits!
目の前の扉を開ければそう
If you open the door right in front of you, yes,
終わりのない夜への始まりだ！
it's the start of an endless night!
気球上のフロアの鍵から
From the key to the floor above the balloon,
次元への旅が始まるよ！
the journey to another dimension begins!
流星の百合子乗り越えてさ
Overcoming the meteor's lily,
軸旅行へと進もう！
let's head on an axis journey!
ぎゅっと！ そう ぎゅっと！
Tightly! So, tightly!
思い込め て ぎゅっと！ あたたかい手の中で 転がり続ける Rolling Riceball
Hold on tight and keep spinning, Rolling Riceball!
お弁当をカバンに入れ さあ出かけよう
Pack your bento in your bag, let's head out!
誰も見たことのない 新しい1ページ
A brand new page nobody has ever seen!
ハッピーラッキーモーニング 破茶滅茶ルーティン
Happy lucky morning, breaking all the rules!
楽しいのは 転転転結！
What's most fun is spinning, spinning, spinning on!
(Good!) お弁当♥ (いいね!いいね!)
(Good!) Bento! (Great, great!)
(Good!) 映えスポット♥ (いいね!いいね!)
(Good!) Spotlit! (Great, great!)
想定外!超展開!転がるように Sut-ton-ton
Beyond expectations, grand development, rolling like Sut-ton-ton!
私だけが知っている (打ち出的小槌)
Only I know (The launching riceball)
伝えたい (はい!) 伝えたい (はい!)
I want to tell you! I want to tell you!
Ah 神様…!
Ah, dear God...!
ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
Tightly! (Tightly!)
そう ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
So, tightly! (Tightly!)
思い込め て ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
Hold on tight and believe! (Tightly!)
誰より も速く (はい!)
Faster than anyone! (Yes!)
転がり続ける Rolling Riceball
Keeping on rolling, Rolling Riceball!
もっと! (もっと!)
More! (More!)
そう もっと! (もっと!)
So, more! (More!)
咲き誇る ん だ もっと! (もっと!)
Blooming bright, even more! (More!)
誰より もアツく (はい!)
Aint even hotter! (Yes!)
輝き続ける Shining Fireball
Shining on, Shining Fireball!
私だけ の 神降臨! (はい!)
My very own divine descent! (Yes!)
あめばこ あかい の
Amebako akai no
どー し !? どー し !?
Do shi!? Do shi!?
サイド に ステップ
Side step!
ケン ケン パッパ !
Ken ken pa-pa!
いい じゃ ない !? いい かんじ !?
Ii janai!? Ii kanji!?
神降臨! (はい!)
Divine descent! (Yes!)
お弁当をカバンに入れ さあ出かけよう
Pack your bento in your bag, let's head out!
誰も見たことのない 新しい1ページ
A brand new page nobody has ever seen!
きっと そう きっと
Surely, yes, surely
あなた がいるから
Because you are right here!
あたたかい手の中で
In those warm hands,
世界 とお腹 は ラブ ＆ 平和!
The world and our bellies are love & peace!
ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
Tightly! (Tightly!)
そう ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
So, tightly! (Tightly!)
思い込め て ぎゅっと! (ぎゅっと!)
Hold on tight and believe! (Tightly!)
誰より も速く (はい!)
Faster than anyone! (Yes!)
転がり続ける Rolling Riceball
Keeping on rolling, Rolling Riceball!
もっと! (もっと!)
More! (More!)
そう もっと! (もっと!)
So, more! (More!)
咲き誇る ん だ もっと! (もっと!)
Blooming bright, even more! (More!)
世界 の中心 で
In the center of the world,
無数 のハート に見守られ
Guarded by countless hearts,
照れ隠し でも ありがとう ( ありがとう )
Thank you, even through the shyness! (Thank you!)
あなた がいてくれる
Because you're here with me!
好きだから ( はい ! )
Because I love you! (Yes!)
いえない の ( はい ! )
I can't say it! (Yes!)
転がり 続ける rolling rice ball
Rolling on and on, rolling riceball!
好きだから ( はい ! )
Because I love you! (Yes!)
いえない の ( はい ! )
I can't say it! (Yes!)
輝き 続ける shining fireball
Shining on and on, shining fireball!
私 だけ の 神降臨 ! ( はい ! )
My very own divine descent! (Yes!)
あめばこ くろ い な
Amebako kuroi na
そう でしょう !? そう でしょう !?
Sou desho!? Sou desho!?
ロール ダンス に 千手観音
Roll dance with Avalokiteshvara!
いい じゃ ない !? いい かんじ !?
Ii janai!? Ii kanji!?
神降臨 ( はい ! )
Divine descent! (Yes!)
枯れ木 でもあきらめる な キセキ がある から
Even a withered tree shouldn't give up, 'cause there's a miracle!
無邪気 に 駆け抜けれ ば
If you run through it innocently,
最高 に めでたし
It'll be the absolute best!
全然つかえないきみのこと
Completely ungraspable, you are,
全然知らないうちに
before I even knew it at all,
ココロ奪われるなんてこと
having my heart stolen away—
あるはずないでしょ
there's just no way, right?
メランコリック
Melancholic
それは無愛想な笑顔だったり
Maybe it was a blank, expressionless smile,
それは日曜日の日暮れだったり
maybe it was Sunday at dusk,
それはテストばっかの期間だったり
maybe it was just test-cramming period,
それはきみという名のメランコリンニスト。
that's the melancholicist named you.
手当たり次第強気でぶつかっても
Even if I charge in recklessly, head-first,
なんにも手には残らないって思い込んでる
telling myself nothing will be left in my hands anyway,
ちょっとくらいの勇気にだってちっちゃくなって塞ぎ込んでる
even a little bit of courage has shrunk away and is hiding inside.
わたしだから
'Cause that's just who I am!
全然つかえないきみのこと
Completely ungraspable, you are,
全然知らないうちに
before I even knew it at all,
ココロ奪われるなんてこと
having my heart stolen away—
あるはずないでしょ
there's just no way, right?
「ねえねえ」じゃないわ
A "hey, hey" is out of the question,
この笑顔また眠れないでしょ
with that smile of yours, I won't be able to sleep again tonight!
あしたもおんなじ
Tomorrow too, the same,
わたしが いるのかな
I wonder if I'll be here.
無愛想で無口なままの
Apathetic and quiet all along,
カワイくないヤツ
Such an uncute person.
あの夢にきみが出てきたときから
Ever since you appeared in my dream,
素直じゃないの
I haven't been honest.
だって
Because...
全然つかめないきみのこと 全然知らないうちに
Before I even knew anything about you, who is so hard to grasp,
こころ奪おうとしてたのは わたしのほうだもん
It was actually me who was trying to steal your heart.
そういう時期なの おぼれたいの
It's that kind of phase, I want to drown in it.
いとしのメランコリー
My beloved melancholy.
君の虜になってしまえばきっと
If I were to become your captive,
この夏は充実するのもっと
This summer would be so much more fulfilling.
もう戻れなくたって忘れないで
Even if we can never go back, don't forget.
何年経っても言えない
Even after all these years, I can't say it.
後悔したって構わない
I don't care if I regret it.
でも言葉はここまで出てるの
Yet the words are right up to here.
ねぇサマータイム
Hey, summertime.
海岸通りを歩きたい
I want to walk down the coastal street,
ドライブだってしてみたい
I want to go on a drive too.
ただ視線を合わせてほしいの ねぇサマータイム
I just want you to meet my gaze, hey, summertime.
夜明けまで海辺走って
Running along the beach until dawn,
潮騒に包まれたいね
I want to be wrapped in the sound of the waves.
彼女の仕草が甘いね
Her gestures are so sweet.
君の虜になってしまえばきっと
If I were to become your captive,
この夏は充実するのもっと
This summer would be so much more fulfilling.
噂のドリーミンガール忘れないで
Don't forget the rumored dreaming girl.
でも気持ちを伝えてしまえばいつか
But if I ever convey my feelings,
この夢は覚めてしまうだろうな
This dream would probably wake up.
青い影が揺れる街角
At the street corner where blue shadows sway.
占いなんて信じない
I don't believe in fortunes,
運命なんてあるわけない
Nor do I believe destiny exists.
ただ本当のことを知りたいの
I just want to know the truth.
ねぇサマータイム
Hey, summertime.
近づく距離にも気づかない
Not even noticing the closing distance,
胸の高鳴りごまかせない
I can't hide the pounding of my heart.
でも昔と変わらずニブいの ねぇサマータイム
Yet you're as oblivious as ever, hey, summertime.
思い出は色褪せたって
Even if memories fade away,
惚れた腫れたの仲がいいね
Being passionately in love is nice.
彼女の笑顔が憎いね
Her smile is so frustratingly adorable.
君の虜になってしまえばきっと
If I were to become your captive,
この夏は充実するのもっと
This summer would be so much more fulfilling.
噂のドリーミンガール忘れないで
Don't forget the rumored dreaming girl.
でも気持ちを伝えてしまえばいつか
But if I ever convey my feelings,
この夢は覚めてしまうだろうな
This dream would probably wake up.
青い影が揺れる
Blue shadows sway...
君の虜になってしまえばきっと
If I were to become your captive,
この夏は充実するのもっと
This summer would be so much more fulfilling.
噂のドリーミンガール忘れないで
Don't forget the rumored dreaming girl.
噂のドリーミングガール 忘れないで
でも気持ちを伝えてしまえばいつか この夢は覚めてしまうだろうな
But if I ever convey my feelings, this dream will probably wake up someday.
青い影が揺れる街角
A street corner where blue shadows sway.
やあ、みんな！LAMB VEGAS AMAZING SWING 楽しんでますかー？
Hey everyone! Are you enjoying LAMB VEGAS AMAZING SWING?
いや、バカタレサーカスでね、新曲と、これはもう、アゲアゲな曲を、え、最初にね、ちょっとぶっ放したかったので、え、その新曲にさせていただいて、
Well, with Bakatare Circus, we wanted to kick things off with a high-energy new song, so we started with that one.
で、ボタンちゃんとあ、メランコリック、なんか、甘酸っぱい、え、な、え、好きなの？どんな？くっついちゃうの？え、どうなの？みたいな
And with Botan-chan, "Melancholic"—it's kind of bittersweet, like "Do you like them? Do you get close? How is it?"—
感じのね、甘酸っぱい曲を一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました！そしてなんとファウナとも、え、
we sang and danced to that bittersweet song together! And what's more, with Fauna too, um—
初めてわための記念配信で3Dでね、一緒に歌って踊って、サマータイムちょっとね、わためが、あの、男声のねパートをやらせていただいて、
for the first time in Watame's anniversary stream in 3D, we sang and danced together. For Summertime, Watame did the male vocal part,
で、ファウナちゃんが女声のパートをね、歌って踊っていただいて、どうだったかな？どうだったかな？ちょっとね、やってみたかったんだよね全部。楽しんでらえてたら、た
and Fauna-chan sang and danced the female vocal part. How was it? How was it? I really wanted to try doing all of that. If you enjoyed it all,
楽しい？楽しい？ありがと、楽しい！あっつじゃない、あつじゃないからね！ありがとうございます。でもまだまだ終わらない！ここからゲストパート後半戦です！うーん、楽しんでいこー！
was it fun? Was it fun? Thank you, it was fun! Not hot—well, it's not hot! Thank you very much. But it's not over yet! From here on is the second half of the guest part! Yeah, let's keep enjoying it!
ねぇドクター ねえドクター メンテしてよドクター またいつものレインボウガール
Hey doctor, hey doctor, maintain me, doctor. Once again, the usual rainbow girl.
HAPPY OR LUCKY 行き来するMOTOR 組み立てて全脳式ノココロどこだ
HAPPY OR LUCKY, a motor going back and forth. Assemble a brain-style heart—where is it?
おかしね おかしね くだらないね イェイイェイ わけないね わけないね ハイペックなんて
Funny, right? Funny, right? So silly, yeah, yeah. No way, no way, being high-spec...
させられたのぽ? ならまぎょそ ドキドキが止まりそう ねじまいって
Were you made to do that? Then... My heart is about to stop, wind it up!
狂ってゆけ エソテリックで ねじまいて ねじまいてよ ちょっとだけね ちょっちょ ちょっとだけね
Go crazy, esoterically. Wind it up, wind it up, just a little bit, just a little bit.
ピッポパッポ鳴らして 夢を作る ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね いつかはとらえてじゃん そのうちてなくなるかも
Make pippo-pappo sounds and create dreams. Just a little bit, just a little bit. Someday we'll catch it, before it disappears.
リルビリルビリルビモア ねえドクター ねえドクター メンテしたのドクター
Lilvi lilvi lilvi more. Hey doctor, hey doctor, did you maintain me, doctor?
出るから出るからワクワクだからなななな
It's coming out, coming out, because I'm excited, na-na-na-na.
なんかおかしいね おかしいね とんでもないね イェイイェイ これはもうテクノロジーだ
Something's funny, right? Funny, right? Outrageous, yeah, yeah. This is already technology.
3次元だってメモッてるの 分かったら そのペレスぐまいって
Even in 3D, I'm taking notes. Once you understand, wind that perez up!
4じぇけもわのあって ねじまいて ねじまいてよ ちょっとだけね ちょっちょ ちょっとだけね
Wind it up, wind it up, just a little bit, just a little bit.
君が魅せの終わらせてあげる ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね ほらどこからどこからアイデンティティアップデートして どうもありがとう 心から リルビ リルビ リルビモア
I'll let you see the end. Just a little bit, just a little bit. Look, from where, updating identity—thank you so much from the bottom of my heart, lilvi lilvi lilvi more.
ピッポパッポ ピッピポ パッポピッコン クリシー アクションセ
Pippo-pappo, pippipo, pappopikkon, click-clack, action set.
起きて起きて 手のひら羊 こちらに気を合わせて
Wake up, wake up, palm sheep, pay attention here.
その前にひとまずねじまいって
Before that, wind it up for now.
狂ってゆけ エソテリックで ねじまいて ねじまいてよ ちょっとだけね ちょっちょ ちょっとだけね おねめ
Go crazy, esoterically. Wind it up, wind it up, just a little bit, just a little bit.
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit.
もわもわなものいいけどお・り・さ・ま・き・ゅ・ん
Fluffy things are nice, but...
ちょっとだけね
just a little bit.
Just a little bit.
こんなまいにちもわるくないよちょっとだけね
Even days like this aren't bad, just a little bit.
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit.
でもちょっとだけじゃそのうち楽しくなるかも
But if it's just a little, you might start having fun soon.
びるびるびるびるびるびるびるもー
Building, building, building more!
もー
Geez!
未来を隠す箱
A box hiding the future,
秘宝に香る危なげな
carrying a dangerous, fragrant treasure.
dangerous わたばりに進める
Dangerous... pressing onward through the fluff,
I'm Your Treasure Box
これ開けたら君たちにななんて言ってあげればいいかな
What should I say to you all when I open this up?
探してたのは船長
"Were you looking for Senchou?"
そんなにがっついちゃだめだぞ
"Don't be so overly eager!"
お宝よりも魅惑的なもの見つけちゃった？いいじゃん
Did you find something more attractive than treasure? How nice.
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝 それは私
The inviting red of garnet, the ultimate pirate's treasure, that's me.
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうかしばらくしないで 開けてみて
Overflowing with allure, please don't be afraid of the fragrance, open it and see.
雨が降ってきたよ 香りもとかこうは上がらないぜ
It started raining, and the fragrance...
開けてみて
Open it and see.
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチブー 船長つかまえたいくない？
Sexy number one in the world, super perky and fresh. Don't you want to capture the Captain?
You're gonna get the treasure Maybe tasting me 私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You're gonna get the treasure, maybe tasting me. You want my sweetness, don't you?
秘宝の鍵を優しくだして 宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
Gently insert the key of the secret treasure, hurry up and open the door of the vault!
じれったい貴方の手 海図こぼす甘いため息のTease
Your impatient hands, a tease of sweet sighs spilled over the nautical chart.
純紅のバラがしおれる前に We will sail the seven seas
Before the crimson roses wither, we will sail the seven seas!
夏のまぶしさに 輝くオーシャンマリン またね出逢うから何に想像しての
Summer sun smiling with glee, shining ocean of marine. What are you imagining...
今すぐ開けてよ 宝箱
Open up this box right now, treasure box.
泣く子も黙る naughty 悩殺ビーム キミたちももう我慢できなくなる？
Naughty seduction beam that even crying children quiet down to. Can't you guys stand it anymore either?
You're gonna own the pleasure Maybe love of me 私の全てを手に入れて
You're gonna own the pleasure, maybe love of me. Take all of me into your hands.
金銀財宝はした金でしょ しわしわになっちゃう誰か助けて
Gold and silver treasures are mere pocket change, I'll shrivel up, someone help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ キミたち何考えてんの 分かってるんだわ 欲望だから今すぐ開けてよ宝箱
You're holding back way too much, what are you guys thinking? I know you're craving it, open the treasure box right now!
Open up this box Open it right now or I will scream あああっ
Open up this box, open it right now or I will scream! Ahhhh!
貴方を待つガネット… キミたち開けてーー！！
The garnet waiting for you... You guys, open it up~~!!
You're on the pleasure Maybe double me 私のすべてを手に入れて
You're on the pleasure, maybe double me. Take all of my everything into your hands!
金金ざるほど 稼いでるなりのおさび きみたちもおがまんできなくなる？
Earning gold like a sieve, can't you guys hold back anymore either?
Your on the pleasure Maybe double me 私のすべてを手に入れて
You're on the pleasure, maybe double me. Take all of my everything into your hands!
だから今すぐ開けてよ 宝箱 あなたが待つがねと
So open up this box right now, the garnet waiting for you...
キミたち開けてーー！！
You guys, open it up~~!!
あああっ！
Ahhh!
描いた 未知のキャンバス
Painted unknown canvas
重ねる景色
Overlapping scenery
繋いでみて 繰り返していく衝動
Connect them and repeat the impulse
煌めいた
Glittering
目の前に広がる世界
The world spreading before my eyes
星屑のメロディ 歌に乗せた
Stardust melody set to song
クラッと鮮やかに 眩ませるように
Dizzily, vividly, to dazzle
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
Run through, starlight
we can fly そう僕らは
we can fly, yes, we
いつしか夢の中 引かれていた
Someday drawn into a dream
ただむしゃらに走り続けたよ
Just kept running recklessly
無限の宇宙に響いてた キミを照らす声は
The voice illuminating you that echoed in the infinite universe
どこへだってきらり飛んでいけるんだ
Can fly brilliantly anywhere
陽気な仲間と
With cheerful companions
歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days we walked
掴んでみて 指先の一等星
Try to grasp the first-magnitude star at your fingertips
滲んでいく
Blurring
目の前に広がった限界は
The limits that spread before my eyes
みんなの手重ねてぶっ壊して
Destroyed by stacking everyone's hands
吸い込まれそうな 夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that looks like it'll suck us in
今叫ぶよ スターライト
Now I shout, starlight
i wanna be そう僕らは
i wanna be, yes, we
いつでもそばで笑い合って
Always smiling together by each other's side
あふれる声が 遠くこだまする
The overflowing voice echoes far away
願いのかけらを灯した キミの腕を引いて
Pulling your arm, having lit the fragments of our wishes
どこへだってきらり飛んでいけるんだ
We can fly brilliantly anywhere
ちょっと不安な日も
Even on slightly uneasy days
魔法をかけてハッピー
Cast a spell and be happy
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with superhuman strength
アクアブルーに染まる
Dyed in aqua blue
大空にめがけた
Aimed at the vast sky
鼓動が弾んでく
Our heartbeats are bounding
we can fly そう僕らは
we can fly, yes, we
この日をずっと待ってたんだ
Have been waiting for this day all along
まだ覚めないで
Don't wake up yet
starlight 僕らは止まらない
starlight, we won't stop
その光が消える1秒前まで走り続けるよ
I will keep running until 1 second before that light fades
無限の宇宙に響いてた キミを照らす声を
The voice illuminating you that echoed in the infinite universe
強く抱いてきらり輝いていけ
Hold it tight and shine brilliantly
やあ！楽しいね！
Yay! This is so fun!
いや、ゲストパートもね、ひと区切りつきまして、
Well, the guest part has wrapped up, and
このロボ子ちゃんと、マリンちゃんと、スバルちゃんと
with Roboco-chan, Marine-chan, and Subaru-chan,
かなり珍しい組み合わせだったのではないでしょうか？
wasn't this quite a rare combination?
でもね、もうずっとずっと呼びたいと思ってたね。
But you know, I've wanted to invite them for so long.
みんなだからね、こうやって一緒に歌って、踊って、なんかね、
So everyone, singing and dancing together like this,
セクシーな感じもね、出せたりとか、かっこいい感じも出せたりとか
giving off a sexy vibe or a cool vibe as well,
ね、してたよね？セクシーじゃない！
you know, we did, right? Not sexy!
し、してたよね？あれはセクシーだったよね？
W-we did, right? That was sexy, right?
ね？ま、ね、いろんな、まあ、わためをちょっと見てもらえたんじゃないかなと思って
Right? Well, you know, I hope you got to see various sides of Watame
おります。ま、もうね、活動4周年ですから
for our 4th anniversary.
ちょっと成長した姿もね、見せたいななんて、思って
I wanted to show a slightly more grown-up side of me too,
今フェロモン出してるから、見せたいななんて思って頑張りました！
radiating pheromones right now, so I worked hard!
いや、どうだったかな？楽しんでくれてるよね？
Man, how was it? You're enjoying it, right?
いや、わためはとっても楽しいです！いや、めちゃくちゃ楽しい！
Man, Watame is having so much fun! It's super fun!
こうやってね、3Dになって、衣装も
Becoming 3D like this, and with the outfit...
だいぶ増えたよね。
It's increased quite a bit, hasn't it?
こうやって見るとね。
When you look at it like this.
いや なんかその 衣装も 増えたことによって
Yeah, somehow, with those outfits having increased,
隣にこう メンバーと 立って
standing next to members like this,
なんかこう シナジーというか
sort of like synergy,
なんか なんだろうね。
somehow, I wonder what it is.
なんかね、いいよね 語彙力。
Somehow, it's nice, vocabulary.
語彙力はちょっと 5周年 磨きたいなと 思います。
I want to polish my vocabulary a bit for the 5th anniversary.
いやでもまだまだ ここでは 終わりませんので、
But hey, it's still far from over here,
この先も ぜひ見てほしいなと 思って ます。
so I hope you'll check out what's ahead too.
いや それも
Yeah, and that too,
あれなんだよ サムネ 見ていただけたかな
I wonder if you saw the thumbnail,
見てるよね 待機中とかね たぶん見れるもんね
well you're watching, right, while waiting you can probably see it,
そうだよね ホロジュールとか載ってるもんね。
that's right, it's listed on Holojump and things.
あの、文字見ましたか。
Did you see those letters?
し、しん？ し、い、い、い、衣装なんか おひろ、おひろめがあるとか お お お
Th- Th- Th- There's an outfit reveal or s-s-something?
それも、ま、もう後半戦だからね、あったりするんじゃない、な、ないかな、ね、見たいよね。
And since it's the second half now, won't there be one? Wouldn't there? You wanna see it, right?
いや、おねがい、みて、おねがい見て、がんばるんで。
Please, check it out, please check it out, I'll do my best!
見て、欲しいなと 思います。
I hope you'll check it out.
では ふう、落ち着いてね。
Now then, phew, calm down.
よし、では 次の曲 聞いてください。レインボー。
Alright, now please listen to the next song. Rainbow.
ねえ おはようの後 もう落ち込んでるの
Hey, right after "Good morning," I'm already feeling down
ああ やりたいことも 怖い 叶い目にしたい
Ah, things I want to do too, want to make it a scary encounter
もう ちょっと だけの 自分 もう 一歩 が踏み出せない
Just a little more of myself, I can't take another step forward
そう言えば オッケーだった
Come to think of it, that was okay
逃げて いられた
I was able to run away
でも 君が笑って それでもいいと言うなら
But if you smile and say even that is fine,
恥ずかしいところとか ダメなところとか 見せたくなくなっちゃうでしょ
then you wouldn't want to show your embarrassing or pathetic sides
どんな時も 前を向いて 歌っていたい ほらへこんでないで辛い時も
At any time, looking forward, I want to sing. Look, even when you're depressed or having a hard time
強がってるけど 平気だよ きっと君のためならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine. Surely, for your sake, there are things I can do
涙を大嫌いにバラまいて 弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Scattering tears as if I hate them, even if weak, I can summon a rainbow
また明日も 多分僕次第で 今日よりも輝いてく
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me, will shine even brighter than today
ねえ おはようの後 なんだか気分がいい
Hey, right after "Good morning," somehow I feel in a good mood
もう 繰り返しとか ないそう思えるよ
I can think that there won't be repetitions anymore
意外と怖くないね あくまで個人の感想です
It's surprisingly not scary. This is just my personal opinion
決められた力とか 見たことない奇跡とか そんなの忘れちゃうかも
Prescribed power or miracles I've never seen, I might forget all about that
呼び込んで僕は変わる 合図は君に出してほしい
Inviting it in, I change. I want you to give me the signal
大冒険する準備なら ちゃんと君の分までしたよ
If you're ready for a big adventure, I've prepared enough for your share too
どんな時も 前を向いて 歌っていたい ほらへこんでないで辛い時も
At any time, looking forward, I want to sing. Look, even when you're depressed or having a hard time
強がってるけど 平気だよ きっと君のためならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine. Surely, for your sake, there are things I can do
涙を大嫌いにバラまいて 弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Scattering tears as if I hate them, even if weak, I can summon a rainbow
また明日も 多分僕次第で 今日よりも輝いてく
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me, will shine even brighter than today
期待のルーキーはシープなホープ
The promising rookie is a sheepish hope,
その頭のホーンがさらにキュート
and those horns on her head are even cuter.
このくるくる巻いてるクールなムーブに
With this curly-winding, cool groove,
売るほどあるぜ良質なウール
there's plenty of high-quality wool to sell!
ハサミでちょき
Snip with scissors,
バリカンでスーッ
swoosh with clippers!
あったか毛布直販でスー
Warm blankets, direct sales!
なんと今日お買い上げいただくとさらにもう一個付いてきまスー
What's more, buy today and get another one free!
混迷する混濁の世界鮮やかに救う救世主
A savior brightly rescuing a chaotic, murky world—
コットン、リネン、レーヨンにアクリル、シルク、ナイロンにポリエステル
cotton, linen, rayon, acrylic, silk, nylon, polyester!
一方こちら天然のウール
On the other hand, here is natural wool,
合成繊維戦意喪失
synthetic fibers have lost their will to fight!
元気ない奴はここにこな
Lifeless folks, come here,
心の綿パンパンにしてやんよ
let's stuff your cotton hearts full!
よく晴れた日、光浴びて
On a clear day, basking in the light,
膨らませよう心の綿毛
let's fluff up the down of our hearts.
寒い日には温めるよ
On cold days, I'll warm you up,
それがわたくし、わための役目
that is my duty as Watame!
白い雲に似せてこんな広い空にうかべたらどうでしょ
Like white clouds, how about floating them in such a wide sky?
眠れない夜は私の名を呼んで
On sleepless nights, call my name,
素敵な夢に一名様をご招待
inviting one guest to a wonderful dream.
眠れない夜は私を思い出して
On sleepless nights, remember me,
楽しい夢にみんなをまとめて連れて行くよ
gathering everyone to take them to a happy dream—
わためいすたー
WataMeister!
かちかちのざらめが進化した最高の魔改造
The hardened sugar crystal evolved into the ultimate dark remodel—
色とりどりのふわふわの夢詰め込まれている奇跡のおかし
a miraculous treat stuffed with colorful, fluffy dreams!
わためのわたがしなら食べ放題だぜ
If it's Watame's cotton candy, it's all-you-can-eat!
この業務用マシンのスペックなら1分で2本のハイパースピード製造OK
With this commercial machine's specs, high-speed production of two per minute is OK!
行列のできる綿あめ屋の道のりは長い険しく甘くない
The road to the popular cotton candy shop is long, steep, and not sweet.
溶けたざらめに届くフレーバーカラフルな色で無数の創造性
Flavors reaching melted sugar, countless creativity in colorful hues,
宇宙に輝く星々にも似た割りばしでつかむ輝く宝石
shining jewels grasped with disposable chopsticks, resembling stars shining in space.
町内会の縁日の祭りに欠かせない必須アイテム参上
The essential item indispensable for the neighborhood association's festival has arrived!
甘い香りのせてこんな広い空にうかべたらどうでしょ
Carried on a sweet scent, how about floating them in such a wide sky?
愉快な仲間と同じ時過ごして
Spending the same time with jolly companions,
気付いたらだいぶ遠くまで歩いてた
before I knew it, I had walked quite far.
いつもみんながいたから支えられてここまで来ました
Because everyone was always there supporting me, I've come this far.
お礼と言ってはなんですが
As a token of my gratitude—
さん、はい！
Three, four!
眠れない夜は私の名を呼んで
On sleepless nights, call my name,
素敵な夢に一名様をご招待
inviting one guest to a wonderful dream.
眠れない夜は私を思い出して
On sleepless nights, remember me,
楽しい夢にみんなをまとめて連れて行くよ
gathering everyone to take them to a happy dream—
わためいすたー
WataMeister!
はあ！
Whew!
どうだったかな、レインボー
How was it, Rainbow?
そして新曲の「わためいすたー」という曲を歌わせていただきました！
And I got to sing my new song called "WataMeister"!
いやー！
Man!
なんとね、わためいすたー、こちら作詞、作曲、編曲がケンモチヒデフミさんにお願いした曲になりまして
You know, WataMeister, this song's lyrics, composition, and arrangement were requested from Kenmochi Hidefumi-san,
ちょっとね、歌詞とかも不思議な感じがあったかなと思うんですけど、こちらアルバムに入ってます
and I think the lyrics have a rather mysterious feel to them, but this is included in the album,
ホップステップシンプに入ってますので
it's in "Hop Step Sheep", so...
ってること まだあるよね。
There's still some things left to do, right?
まだまだあるよね。
There's still so much more!
わためぇの姿がー！
Watame's appearance—!
甲冑わたはー！
Katchuu Watame—!
ということで、こちら100万人記念で新しい3Dのお衣装を作っていただきましたー！
And so, for my 1-million-subscriber milestone, I had this brand-new 3D outfit made for me!
いやみんなのおかげで、このお衣装を着ることができたんだよ！
It's all thanks to everyone that I was able to wear this outfit!
本当にありがとう！チャンネル登録とかもね、たくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much for all the channel subscriptions as well!
そしてね、おめでとうもいっぱいいっぱいありがとうございますね！
And also, thank you so, so much for all the "congratulations"!
本当にみんなが作ってくれた、え、衣装と言っても過言ではありません！
It's no exaggeration to say that this outfit was truly created by all of you!
え、ゆっくり見せてもいいかな？い、こだわりポイントいい？ちょっとだけ、いいかな？
Um, is it okay if I show it to you slowly? Um, can I show you the attention to detail? Just a little bit, is that okay?
まず、靴！みてみて！
First, the shoes! Look, look!
かっこいいよね！
They're so cool, right?
今回はね、スポーティーな、そして、え、ダンスもね、結構踊ったりするので、ダンスしやすいそんなお衣装を頼みましたはー！
This time, they're sporty, and since I'll be dancing quite a bit, I asked for an outfit that makes it easy to dance!
いや、すごい。
Man, they're amazing.
そして、太もものー、えー、見る？太ももー。
And also, my thighs—um, wanna see? My thighs—
むちむちな感じがねー。
That plump feeling, haha!
ちょっと、あ、ライブなのに、変態みたい、えー、
Wait, ah, even though this is a live stream, I sound like a pervert, um—
あとはね、しっぽー！なかなかね、わためのお衣装的にしっぽは見えないんだけどね、
And also, my tail! Usually, with Watame's outfits, you can't see the tail, but
今回はがっつり丸見えでございます！あとは、
this time it's completely visible! And also,
脇テープの！ありわはーん！
the armpit tape! Ariwa-haaan!
ふーー！
Woo—!
素晴らしい！この筋が！素晴らしいね！この筋がね！
Wonderful! This muscle line! It's amazing, this muscle line!
あと髪型もね、ちょっとサイドポニーといいますか、高いところからのポニーテール、このクシュッとなってんだよね、頭の上長ね、どうですか？
Also, my hairstyle is a side ponytail, or rather, a high ponytail, and it's scrunched up on top of the head like this. What do you think?
かわいいかな？こちらもね、ふうみんまみれに押し立てしていただきました！
Is it cute? They styled this one full of Fuumin love, too!
でもね、まだこれだけではお、終わらないんだよね！へへへヘ、なんだと思う？
But you know, it doesn't end just with this! Hehe, what do you think it is?
あー！そう、わためはまだ変身をあと一つ残しているのだ！
Ah! That's right, Watame still has one more transformation left!
み、みたい？ははは、みたい？じゃあ、ちょっと着替えちゃおうかな？
Wa-, wanna see? Haha, wanna see? Then, maybe I'll change clothes for a second?
そして、あの曲もね、まだ終わりじゃないので、え、聴いてほしい曲がもう1曲あります！
And also, that song isn't over yet either, so there's one more song I want you to listen to!
まだまだ盛り上がっていきましょう！では、次の曲聴いてください！
Let's keep getting more and more hyped! Now, please listen to the next song!
はち！
Eight!
いつだってそう「僕なんか」って
Always thinking "someone like me,"
佇んでばかりのMayday
lingering in endless Maydays,
つまづいて泣いて 「どうせ」って口癖が染み付いてさ
stumbling and crying, with "whatever" stuck on my lips.
ドライブして
Just drive,
ギア入れて
shift into gear,
パパッと片付けてさあ 踊りましょう
clean it up quickly and let's dance!
誰よりももっともっと
More, even more than anyone else,
点々はどんどんどんどん 今すぐにダイブ 飛び込んでけ
dots keep multiplying, dive right in now!
ダンスできたら 踊ってまあまあ 満身創痍になったって
If you can dance, dance it out even if you're battered and bruised!
捨て身でサバイバルして
Survive with reckless abandon,
オパー！踊っちゃって
oh pa! Dance away,
じゃんけんぽんで勝っちゃって ケッケッケンケンパ 進んじゃって
win at rock-paper-scissors and hop, hop, hop forward!
かまって可能性 感じちゃって
Feeling the possibility of wanting attention,
Now on step
徒然 半分ビートの上
Idly on half-beats,
それぞれ 揺らしてくこの場で
shaking it up together in this place.
スライドして
Slide it,
つま弾いて
pluck it,
ここここここ
right here, here, here!
スレスレ波打つカップの上
Right on the brink of a rippling cup,
ズレズレもつれた拍子の上の
on top of tangled, off-beat rhythms,
ドドド ドド ドライブして
driving on and on,
ギギ ギギギ ギア入れて
putting it into gear,
パパ パパッと片付けて
wrapping things up quickly,
さあ 踊りましょう
come on, let's dance!
誰よりも 没頭 もっと
More immersed than anyone else,
点々は ドット ドット
dots are dot dot,
今すぐに ダイビング 飛び込んでけ
dive right in right now!
ダダ ダダ ダダダ
Dada...
ダンシン ただ 踊ったって
just dancing away,
ま ままま 満身創痍 なったって
even if I'm covered in wounds,
step 捨て身で すれ違って
misstepping with a reckless heart,
（オッケー！踊っちゃって）
(Okay! Just dance!)
ジャ ジャジャ ジャンケンポンで 勝っちゃって
Win with rock-paper-scissors,
ケケケ ケケンパ 進んじゃって
hop skip and jump right through,
かまって 可能性 感じちゃって
feeling the possibility of attention,
つまり now on step
in short, now on step!
徒然 半分 ビートの上
Half in reverie, on the beat,
それぞれ ゆらし てく この場で
swaying each in our own way here.
ス スス ス スライドして
Sliding along,
つ つつ つ つま弾いて
plucking away,
こ こここ 今夜も
right here, tonight too,
さあ 踊りましょう
come on, let's dance!
音 鳴らせ もっともっと
Make the music ring out, more and more!
神様は ゴッド ゴッド 楽しみたいならフロアへ直行
God is great, if you want fun, head straight to the floor!
ダダ ダダ ダダダ ダンシン まだ 踊っちゃって
Dada... still dancing away,
か かか 関係ない 朝まで ステップ スベっても気にしないで
it doesn't matter until morning, even if you misstep, don't worry!
（オッケー！踊っちゃって） ざ ざざ 斬新 ただ 笑っちゃって
(Okay! Just dance!) Brand new, just laughing it off,
て てて 天然だって ハッピーで
being natural and happy,
回って 万能性 感じちゃって つまり now on step
spinning around and feeling almighty, in short, now on step!
（おっ おー） 踊ってる?
(Oh oh) Are you dancing?
（おっ おー） ゆらいでる?
(Oh oh) Are you swaying?
ミラーボールが回ってる
The mirror ball is spinning around,
（もっと 踊っていたい）
(and I want to keep dancing more!)
（おっ おー） 踊ってる? （おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) Are you dancing? (Oh oh) Come on and dance!
終わりが来るまで ずっと 踊り明かそう
Let's dance the night away until the end comes!
誰よりも 没頭 もっと
More immersed than anyone else,
点々は ドット ドット
dots are dot dot,
今すぐに ダイビング 飛び込んでけ
dive right in right now!
ダダ ダダ ダダダ
Dada...
ダンシン ただ 踊ったって
just dancing away,
ま ままま 満身創痍 なったって
even if I'm covered in wounds,
step 捨て身で すれ違って
misstepping with a reckless heart,
（オッケー！踊っちゃって）
(Okay! Just dance!)
ジャ ジャジャ ジャンケンポンで 勝っちゃって
Win with rock-paper-scissors,
ケケケ ケケンパ 進んじゃって
hop skip and jump right through,
かまって 可能性 感じちゃって
feeling the possibility of attention,
つまり now on step
in short, now on step!
（おっ おー） 踊ってよう
(Oh oh) Let's keep dancing,
（おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) dance along!
（おっ おー） 踊ってよう
(Oh oh) Let's keep dancing,
（おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) dance along!
（おっ おー） 踊ってよう
(Oh oh) Let's keep dancing,
（おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) dance along!
（おっ おー） 踊ってよう
(Oh oh) Let's keep dancing,
（おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) dance along!
（おっ おー） 踊ってよう
(Oh oh) Let's keep dancing,
（おっ おー） 踊ってよ
(Oh oh) dance along!
はぁー みんな 今日は本当にありがとう！
Haah... Everyone, thank you so much today!
いや、とっても楽しかったよー！
Man, it was so much fun!
いや、新曲の「Now on step」という曲を歌って踊らせていただきました！
Yeah, I got to sing and dance to my new song called "Now on step"!
これはね、えーみんなにぜひ、あのサビの振り付けをね、踊ってもらいたいなと思って、ひるみ先生にね、振り付け作っていただいたので、一緒にたくさん踊って騒ぎましょう！
I wanted everyone to dance along to the chorus choreography, so Hirumi-sensei made it for us, let's dance and make some noise together!
これからもね、いや本当にありがとう！いや、4周年か、早いな！
From now on too... thank you so much! Man, 4th anniversary already, time flies!
でも、こうずっと笑顔を、た、たやすこ、まあ泣いたりもするけど、でもあの楽しく、本当に今もこうやってわためが動き回れているのもみんなのおかげだと思っておりますので
Keeping a smile always... I might cry sometimes too, but because we're having fun, and even now Watame is able to run around like this, I believe it's all thanks to everyone,
いや本当に感謝ありがとう！
so I am truly grateful, thank you!
今日初めて知ってくれた人も、今までずっと応援してくれてる人も、これからは5周年に向けて、まだまだドドの羊頑張っていきますので、どうぞ応援よろしくお願いします！
To those who found out about me today, and those who have supported me all along, heading towards the 5th anniversary, Dodono Sheep will keep working hard, so please continue your support!
本当にありがとう、楽しいこといっぱいこれからもしていきましょう！
Thank you so much, let's keep doing lots of fun things together from now on!
お、この後いろいろ告知もあるので、チャンネルはそのままでお楽しみにな！
Oh, there are various announcements after this, so stay tuned on this channel!
さらに、そのあとのメンゲンではこの新衣装のパーカーバージョンもゆっくりお披露目したり、歌ったりしていきたいなと思ってますので、みんなぜひ遊びに来てください！
Furthermore, in the following membership stream, I plan to slowly unveil and sing in the hoodie version of this new outfit, so everyone please come join us!
今日は本当にありがとう！これからもよろしく！
Thank you so much today! See you next time!
聞くのが心地よい曲かなと思うので、
I think it's a very comforting song to listen to,
ぜひわためのアルバム「Hop Step Sheep」をゲットして、なん度でも聴いてください。
so please get my album "Hop Step Sheep" and listen to it as many times as you like!
そして、最後に歌った楽曲は、
And the last song I sang
「Now on step」という楽曲で、
is a track called "Now on step".
この楽曲は以前にも「音故知新の歌ととわなる未来」という曲を作っていただいた佐藤陽介さんに制作していただきました！
This song was produced by Yosuke Sato, who previously created "Onko Chishin no Uta to Towanaru Mirai" for me!
みんなと一緒に歌って踊って楽しめる曲になってますので、1月31日のセカンドライブで一緒に盛り上がりましょう！
It's a song we can all sing, dance, and have fun with together, so let's get hyped together at my 2nd live on January 31st!
このあとすぐ「Now on step」のMVも投稿されるので、ぜひ見てください。
The MV for "Now on step" will also be posted right after this, so please check it out.
振りの方もショート動画を上げる予定なので、練習よろしくお願いします！
I'm planning to upload short videos for the choreography too, so please practice!
そして、なんとこのあと24時から楽曲配信もあります！「Now on step」たくさん聴いてください。よろしくお願いします！
And what's more, starting at midnight tonight, the song will also be available for streaming! Please listen to "Now on step" a lot. Thank you!
穴が空くほど聴いて、振りもたくさん練習して、1月31日めちゃくちゃ楽しいライブにしましょう！
Listen to it until holes are worn through, practice the choreography a lot, and let's make January 31st an insanely fun live!
そんな31日、もう一回おさらいです。
For that 31st, here is a recap once again.
角巻わため 2nd Live「わためぇ Night Fever!! in TOKYO GARDEN THEATER」が、来月の1月31日にあります！
Tsunomaki Watame 2nd Live "Watamée Night Fever!! in TOKYO GARDEN THEATER" will be held next month on January 31st!
チケット販売リンクや特設サイトなど概要欄に記載してあるので、ぜひチェックしてみてください。配信チケットなどもあります！
Ticket purchase links and the special site are in the description box, so please be sure to check them out. Streaming tickets are also available!
そして、なんと、なんと！全国の書店とのコラボキャンペーンが開催決定！
And what's more, a nationwide bookstore collaboration campaign has been confirmed!
対象書店でお買い物時にノベルティをプレゼントさせていただきます。
When you make a purchase at eligible bookstores, you'll receive a novelty gift.
ノベルティには描き下ろしミニキャライラストやメッセージが入っており、対象書店ではライブのキービジュアルを使用したポスターが掲示されたり、
The novelty includes newly drawn mini-character illustrations and a message, and at eligible bookstores, posters using the live's key visual will be displayed,
さらに一部の書店では角巻わための楽曲や特別な店内音声も放送されます！
and what's more, at some bookstores, Tsunomaki Watame's songs and special in-store announcements will be broadcast!
実施期間は2024年1月12日からライブが開催される1月31日まで！
The campaign runs from January 12, 2024, until the live concert on January 31!
企画の詳細や対象店舗はこのあと公開される本の引き出しの記事をチェックしてみてください。
Please check the article on Hon no Hikidashi, which will be published right after this, for details and eligible stores.
まだまだ告知があります！角巻わため4周年記念グッズがこのあと販売されます！詳細は、こちら！
There are still more announcements! Tsunomaki Watame's 4th anniversary goods will go on sale right after this! Details are right here!
まずはBIGメガネ置きアクリルスタンド！いや、これは可愛すぎませんか？
First is the BIG Glasses Stand! Seriously, isn't this way too cute?
わためなりきりサングラスもかけられます！もちろんメガネもかけられますので、一家に1台、2台、3台、いかがでしょうか？
You can put Watame's cosplay sunglasses on it! Of course, regular glasses work too, so how about 1, 2, or 3 for every household?
こちらのイラスト、なんとふみ先生描き下ろしとなります。ふみママ、いつもありがとう！
This illustration was drawn exclusively by Fuumi-sensei. Fuumi-mama, thank you as always!
イラストが可愛すぎちゃって、置くだけでも癒やされそうだよね。
The illustration is just too cute, it looks like it'll be healing just having it placed there.
お次はノート&ペン！小田沙耶佳先生描き下ろしのA6サイズノートです。
Next up is the notebook and pen! It's an A6 size notebook illustrated by Saya Oda-sensei.
いや、これも可愛いな！小田先生がキャラクターデザインを担当されているゲームがわため大好きで、過去にもわためグッズで描いていただいたことがあるんですが、今回も快く4種類のわためを描いてくださいました！
Man, this is also cute! Saya-sensei is in charge of character design for a game I love, and she has drawn Watame goods for me in the past, but she happily drew four kinds of Watame for this too!
ペンの方はクリックするたびにわためセリフやわためとの表情が変わる仕様になっているので、その時の気分に合わせてクリックしてみてください。いっぱい使ってね！
The pen is designed so that every time you click it, Watame's lines or facial expressions change, so try clicking it to match your mood at the time. Please use it a lot!
そして最後はわためナンバーワンタンブラー！
And lastly, the Watame Number One Tumbler!
おしゃれなデザイン！そして熱いのも冷たいのも行けちゃいます！
Stylish design! And it can handle both hot and cold drinks!
もちろんフタもついています！つまり最強ということです！
Of course it comes with a lid! In other words, it's the ultimate item!
みんなこのタンブラーでおそろっちしましょう！
Everyone let's match with this tumbler!
そして、フルセットをご購入いただいた方には角巻わため箔押し複製サイン&メッセージ入りのハート型ダイカットポストカードと特典ボイスがついてきます！ぜひフルセットで手に入れてください！
And for those who purchase the full set, it comes with a heart-shaped die-cut postcard featuring a hot-stamped replicated signature and message from Tsunomaki Watame, plus a bonus voice! Please be sure to get the full set!
いや、ここまで堂々々っと告知をさせていただきましたが、
Well, I've made all these announcements loud and proud,
え、まとめると、このあと「Now on step」のMVが上がります！そして角巻わため4周年記念グッズ販売開始します！え、そして、え、そのあと、え、メン限ライブがあります！さらにえ、24時からは「Now on step」の楽曲配信があります！
so, to summarize: right after this, the MV for "Now on step" drops! And Tsunomaki Watame's 4th anniversary goods go on sale! And then, right after that, there's a membership-only live! Plus, starting at midnight, "Now on step" streaming is available!
こんな感じかな？言いそめれてないかな？あとライブも来年あります！という感じです。
Is that about right? Did I miss anything? Also, there's a live concert next year too! That's the gist of it.
いや、これからもね、嬉しいこととかみんなも喜んでくれるようなことをたくさん共有していけるように頑張っていきたいと思っているので、5年目も一緒に歩いてくれると嬉しいです。これからもよろしく！楽しいことはまだまだ終わらねえ！
Well, going forward, I want to keep working hard to share lots of happy things and things that make you all happy, so I'd be happy if you walk alongside me into my 5th year as well. Thank you for your continued support! The fun is far from over!
その後の新曲MVや
And look forward to the new music video
メンゲンライブも楽しんでいきましょう！
and the membership live as well!
みんなね、
Everyone,
バタバタすると思うが、
I know you're all going to be busy,
わためはメンゲンライブの準備をしてきますので、
but Watame will be preparing for the membership live,
またそこで会いましょう！
so let's meet up there again!
では、また後ほど。
Well then, see you later.
これからもよろしくね！
Thank you for your continued support!